qik.com 2015-02-27

# Skype Privacy Policy

Skype is committed to respecting your privacy and the confidentiality of your personal data, traffic data and communications content.

This Privacy Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how Skype uses and safeguards the information you provide in using Skype's internet communications, Skype's websites and/or Skype's products.

Please note that Skype is now a part of Microsoft.

## **1\. WHAT INFORMATION DOES SKYPE COLLECT AND USE?**

Skype may gather and use information about you, including (but not limited to) information in the following categories:

(a) Identification data (e.g. name, username, address, telephone number, mobile number, email address);

(b) Profile information (e.g. age, gender, country of residence, language preference and any information that you choose to make available to others as part of your Skype user profile as further described in section 6);

(c) Electronic identification data (e.g. IP addresses, cookies);

(d) Banking and payment information (e.g. credit card information, account number);

(e) Call quality and survey results;

(f) Information about your usage of and interaction with Skype software, products, websites and marketing communications (including computer, platform, device and connection information, client performance information, error reports, device capability, bandwidth, statistics on page views, calling destinations, and traffic to and from our websites, browser type and Skype WiFi enabled hotspot detection and usage statistics);

(g) Products or services ordered and delivered;

(h) The URL of videos that you have selected to appear in your mood message;

(i) Skype test calls made to ECHO123 (which are recorded and played back to the user and deleted thereafter);

(j) List of your contacts and related data (we will give you a choice as to whether you want Skype to use contact lists from other services to populate your Skype contacts);

(k) Your username and password for other email accounts where you have provided this to us and requested us to search for your friends on Skype (please note that Skype does not retain this information after completing the search or use it for any other purpose);

(l) Correspondence between you and Skype;

(m) Traffic data (data processed for the purpose of the conveyance of communications or the billing thereof, including, but not limited to, the duration of the call, the number calling and the number called); and

(n) Content of instant messaging communications, Voice messages, and video messages (please see section 12);

(o) Location information, derived from your mobile carrier or from the mobile device that you use, and as described in further detail in section 16, below;

(p) Mobile device information, such as manufacturer’s name, device model number, operating system, carrier network;

(q) Location information, device identifiers and standard identifiers of the Wi-Fi networks your device detects, when you search for or connect to a WiFi hotspot;

(r) Access tokens for other accounts you associate with your Skype account (such as Microsoft account or Facebook), which are like an electronic key provided by the service that acts in place of a password for authentication.

## **2\. HOW DOES SKYPE USE THIS INFORMATION AND FOR WHAT PURPOSE?**

Our primary purpose in collecting information is to provide you with a safe, smooth, efficient, and customized experience. Skype collects and uses, or has third party service providers acting on Skype’s behalf collecting and using, personal data relating to you, as permitted or necessary to:

  * provide internet communication, video sharing and other products in particular to convey the communications and videos you and others make by means of the Skype software and/or the Skype products;
  * change and customize Skype features and functionality;
  * take, process or deliver orders made via our websites, invoice you or notify you of the status of your order;
  * provide other services for you (as described when we collect the information);
  * provide you with customer support and troubleshoot problems;
  * compare information for accuracy;
  * inform you about service updates and faults;
  * request feedback or participation in on-line surveys;
  * resolve disputes;
  * verify your identity;
  * customize, measure, and improve Skype software and websites, as well as other Microsoft products and services;
  * improve our search functionality and help you find and contact other Skype users more easily and accurately;
  * organise and carry out Skype’s marketing or promotional operations/offers, contests, games and similar events;
  * offer certain Skype software, features and websites, free of charge through the support of advertising (please see section 5 for more detail); and
  * protect your and Skype’s interests, including in particular to enforce our Terms of Use and prevent and fight against fraud, (together, the Purposes).

## **3\. OUR DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Except as provided below, Skype will not sell, rent, trade or otherwise transfer any personal and/or traffic data or communications content outside of Microsoft and its controlled subsidiaries and affiliates without your explicit permission, unless it is obliged to do so under applicable laws or by order of the competent authorities. Please note that information that you voluntarily make public in your user profile, or which you disclose on forums, discussions boards or by posting comments will be publicly available and viewable by others.

We may access, disclose and preserve personal data, including your private content (such as the content of your instant messages, stored video messages, voicemails or file transfers), when we have a good faith belief that doing so is necessary to: comply with applicable law or respond to valid legal process from competent authorities, including from law enforcement or other government agencies; protect our customers, for example to prevent spam or attempts to defraud our users, or to help prevent the loss of life or serious injury of anyone; operate and maintain the security of our websites, products and services, including to prevent or stop an attack on our computer systems or networks; or protect our rights or property including enforcing the terms governing the use of our websites, products or services – however, if we receive information indicating that someone is using our products to traffic in stolen intellectual or physical property of Skype or Microsoft, we will not inspect a customer’s private communications or documents ourselves, but we may refer the matter to law enforcement.

In order to provide you with Skype products you have requested, Skype may sometimes, if necessary, share your personal and traffic data with Skype’s group companies, carriers, partner service providers and/or agents. For example the PSTN-VoIP gateway provider, WiFi access services providers, distributors of Skype software and/or Skype products, and/or the third party banking organizations or other providers of payment, email delivery, analytical services, customer support, or hosting services. Skype will always require these third parties to take appropriate organizational and technical measures to protect your personal data and traffic data and to observe the relevant legislation.

Some Skype products may be (i) co-branded; (ii) made available via a partner company’s website; and/or (iii) supported through a partner company. If you register for or use such products, you consent to both Skype’s and the partner company’s use of personal data collected in connection with the product and you understand that the partner company’s use of your personal data may be subject to the partner company’s privacy policy. Skype may offer its products in connection with other websites or services or may team with other online services to give you the combined results of both products/services or additional services and benefits. To determine whether you would benefit from the combined offer, if you have provided your consent, Skype may match your email address, and email addresses of your contacts against email addresses you have provided to the third party website/service provider.

If you are a member of the Skype Manager, detailed information about the activity on your Skype account including traffic data and details of your purchases and downloads may be accessed by your Skype Manager Administrator if you have agreed to such access. You can withdraw your agreement at any time by changing the settings on your account page on www.skype.com. If you provide personal data including your name and job title to be included in the Skype Manager directory, you acknowledge that such data may be viewed by other members of the Skype Manager.

Skype, Skype's local partner, or the operator or company facilitating your communication may provide personal data, communications content and/or traffic data to an appropriate judicial, law enforcement or government authority lawfully requesting such information. Skype may provide reasonable assistance and information to fulfill such request and you hereby consent to such disclosure.

Information that is collected by or sent to Skype and/or Microsoft may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Microsoft or its affiliates, subsidiaries, or service providers maintain facilities. In this regard, or for purposes of sharing or disclosing data in accordance with this article 4, Skype reserves the right to transfer information outside of your country. By using Skype software, Skype's websites or Skype products you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. Microsoft abides by the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Economic Area, and Switzerland. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view our certification, please visit [www.export.gov/safeharbor](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor).

As Microsoft continues to develop its business, Microsoft might sell or buy subsidiaries or business units. In any such transactions in which Skype or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, personal information of Skype users will generally be one of the transferred business assets. We reserve the right to include your personal information in any such transfer to a third party.

## **4\. WHAT ARE COOKIES AND GIFS HOW DOES SKYPE USE THEM?**

Key Points

By using Skype’s websites and/or software you are giving your consent to the use of cookies. You can choose to reject cookies at any time, either by changing your browser settings (if your browser permits) or by ceasing to use Skype’s websites and/or software or by using the applicable opt-out functions. You should be aware that certain features are only available through the use of cookies and if you choose not to accept cookies, such features may not be available to you.

### **4.1 What are Cookies and GIFs?**

#### **4.1.1. Cookies**

Cookies are small files containing a string of characters (text) that are sent to your browser from a website’s server. The cookie may contain a unique identifier but it does not contain personally identifiable information such as your name or email address. Skype may use cookies when you visit its websites, use Skype’s software or visit other websites where Skype serves advertisements. The browser of the Skype software client or your Internet browser stores the cookie on your computer's hard drive and this may be accessed by the website during your next visit. Other websites may also send cookies to your browser but your browser will not allow those websites to see Skype’s cookie data.

A typical Skype cookie might look something like this:  
SC=LC=en:CCY=EUR:CC=UK:TZ=+1:VER=0/1.3.0.13/:TS=1105405660:TM=103841368

SC stands for Skype Cookie (cookie name)  
LC is the language preference for our website  
CCY is the currency preference for our website  
CC is a country code  
TZ is timezone  
VER is the Skype software client version that the user is known to be running  
TS is when the cookie was set  
TM is when the cookie was modified  

#### **4.1.2. Other similar technologies**

Skype web pages and client interfaces may include clear gifs, web-beacons, tracking pixels and other similar electronic images to help deliver cookies on our sites and let us count users who have visited those pages. In addition, we use these images in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened and acted upon and to enable us to recognize you and understand your activity on our websites as a result of these actions. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and track the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns and to tailor your online experience and provide recommendations based on your activity.

### **4.2 What type of Cookies does Skype use?**

Skype uses session cookies, persistent cookies and local shared objects (flash cookies).

Session cookies are temporary cookies, or unique identifiers associated with your browser for the duration of your visit to Skype’s websites or area of the Skype software client. Once you close your browser, the session cookie ID will disappear and information about your visit is not retained.

Persistent Cookies remain on your browser even after you close it and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the website.

Local Shared Objects or ‘Flash Cookies’ are cookies written with Adobe flash technology. These cookies are saved on your computer in the same way as other cookies but they cannot be managed at browser level in the same way.

### **4.3 How Skype uses Cookies**

Skype uses its own cookies for a variety of purposes, including to:

1\. recognize you when you sign in and understand how you arrived at our website, so we can make sure that we provide you with relevant customer content and information. For example:

  * if you arrived at our website by clicking on a link to hear about US subscription packages, we can make sure you see content relevant to those offers;
  * we can recognize your time zone so that your call lists are accurately displayed;
  * if your last purchase included VAT, we can make sure you are always provided with a VAT inclusive price;
  * if your cookie was set a long time ago, we know you are not a new user and we will not show you content intended for new users, such as ‘how to use Skype’ pages;

2\. remember your chosen preferences, such as:

  * the language you choose to see our website in;
  * the currency you wish to see our prices in;

3\. fight against fraud;

4\. inform Skype about the version of the Skype software client you are using so that we can provide you with new software updates and direct you to the relevant help sections;

5\. enable you to access your account and account services through the Skype Software client;

6\. provide internal and customer analytics and gain statistics and metrics about our websites, such as total number of visitors and page views;

7\. monitor the effectiveness and performance of our advertising and marketing campaigns and carry out research in order to help us to improve our products and websites;

8\. initiate security measures such as ‘time-out’ when you have not logged into your account service area for a period of time;

9\. populate your Skype client with one of your Skype contacts’ information, where this contact invited you to join Skype;

10\. deliver video content to you;

11\. provide Skype ads most relevant to you when you visit other sites that display Skype ads.

### **4.4 Third Party Cookies**

In addition to Skype’s cookies, Skype’s analytics, ad-serving and affiliate partners may set cookies and access cookies on your computer, when you are using the Skype software client or visiting a Skype website and may collect information about your online activities across websites or online services.

#### **4.4.1 Analytics**

Skype uses analytics partners, including Omniture, Google Analytics, HockeyApp, and Flurry Analytics, to gather statistical and analytical information about how users use Skype websites and software clients. For example, these partners gather and aggregate data on page views and clicks on our sites, the search engines and keywords used to find our sites, links accessed from our sites, error and crash information about our clients, and similar information. If you have accessed our site from a link in an email that we sent to you, these analytics may be used to effectively target emails that we send to you in the future. These analytics are not used to track your journey to other websites.

#### **4.4.2 Advertising**

The advertisements of Skype and of third parties appearing in the Skype software, Skype products and on third party websites are delivered to you by Microsoft Advertising or other carefully selected ad serving partners (“Ad Serving Partners”).

Skype and its Ad Serving Partners may use non-personally identifiable information that you have provided in your Skype profile or otherwise provided to Skype, such as your age, gender, language and country of residence, as well as information about your relationship with and use of Skype’s websites, software, and products, in order to provide advertisements likely to be of greater interest to you and to help us measure and improve the performance of our advertising campaigns. Skype and our Ad Serving Partners may use cookies and/or web-beacons (Gifs) to collect this information.  

#### **4.4.3. Affiliates**

Skype’s affiliate network program partner allows third parties to introduce people to Skype. Our affiliates may send cookies to your computer to allow them to receive information (a) when you click on a Skype related link on one of our affiliate partner sites, and/or (b) when you make a purchase on Skype’s website, for the purpose of paying commission to the affiliate partner. If you re-visit Skype’s site directly, our affiliate network program partner can recognize you and reward the third-party affiliate partner site that referred you to our site. These cookies are not within Skype’s control and for more information please visit our affiliate network partner Commission Junction’s site at: <http://www.cj.com/privacy>

#### **4.4.4. Other Third Party Content**

Sometimes, Skype’s websites may include widgets or embedded video content from third parties such as YouTube. When you view this content or use this widget, you may be accepting cookies from these websites. These cookies are not within our control and you should check with the relevant third party site for more information.

### **4.5 Your Choices about Cookies**

We don’t recommend that you restrict or block cookies as this may impact on the functionality of our websites and products. However, if you choose to do so, please see the options available to you below. You can also find comprehensive information about cookies at [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

#### **4.5.1 Browser Cookies**

The Help option on the toolbar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, how to delete cookies or how to disable cookies altogether.

Skype software browser cookies can be disabled by: accessing the File menu from your Skype software client toolbar, choosing the Privacy option and un-checking the ‘Allow Skype Browser Cookies’ box.

#### **4.5.2 Local Shared Objects (Flash Cookies)**

You can manage the usage of flash cookies via [http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html).

You may also manage flash cookies through your browser depending on how recent the version of Internet Explorer (or other browser) and media player you are using. Please also visit the Adobe website at <http://kb2.adobe.com/cps/526/52697ee8.html>

#### **4.5.3 Analytics**

To opt out of Omniture analytic cookies, please visit: <https://smetrics.skype.com/optout.html>

To opt out of Google Analytics cookies, please visit: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

To opt out of Flurry Analytics cookies, please visit: <http://www.flurry.com/user-opt-out.html>

#### **4.5.4 Browser Controls for “Do Not Track” and Tracking Protection.**

Some newer browsers have incorporated “Do Not Track” features. Most of these features, when turned on, send a signal or preference to the web sites you visit indicating that you do not wish to be tracked. Those sites (or the third party content on those sites) may continue to engage in activities you might view as tracking even though you have expressed this preference, depending on the sites’ privacy practices.  Because there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret the DNT signal, Microsoft does not currently respond to the browser DNT signals on its own websites or online services, or on third-party websites or online services where Microsoft provides advertisements, content or is otherwise able to collect information.  We continue to work with the online industry to define a common understanding of how to treat DNT signals. In the meantime, users may continue to opt-out of targeted ads from Microsoft as set forth below.

Internet Explorer (versions 9 and up) have a feature called Tracking Protection that helps prevent the web sites you go to from automatically sending details about your visit to third-party content providers. When you add a Tracking Protection List, Internet Explorer will block third-party content, including cookies, from any site that is listed as a site to be blocked. By limiting calls to these sites, Internet Explorer will limit the information these third-party sites can collect about you. For more information about Tracking Protection Lists and Do Not Track, please see the [Internet Explorer Privacy Statement](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=239590) or [Internet Explorer Help](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=298947).

## **5\. YOUR ADVERTISING CHOICES**

Skype websites and some Skype software clients enable third-party advertisements provided by Microsoft Advertising and its Ad Serving Partners. We may use non-personally identifiable information that you have provided to Skype, such as the age, gender, language and country of residence in your Skype profile as well as information about your relationship with and use of Skype’s websites, software, and products, such as the destination of your calls, in order to provide advertisements likely to be of greater interest to you and to help us measure and improve the performance of our advertising campaigns and offers.

These ads may also be targeted based on other information Microsoft Advertising collects outside of Skype’s websites and software. For instance, Microsoft Advertising may utilize the same browser cookies set by Microsoft websites to enhance targeting within the Skype software client.

To learn more about how Microsoft Advertising collects and uses information to target ads on Skype and other properties, including how it uses information collected from Skype, such as age and gender and other information collected as part of delivering ads to or on behalf of Skype to target ads on other properties, please see the Microsoft Advertising Privacy [Statement](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=248689)

If you sign-in to Skype using a Microsoft account or a Skype account that you have linked to a Microsoft account, you may opt-out of receiving targeted ads from Microsoft Advertising by visiting <http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=286759>.

You can also opt out of receiving behaviourally-targeted ads from Microsoft and other advertising companies by visiting the following sites:

1.  In the US:

2.  In Europe:

3.  In Canada:

  * English: [Ad Choices: Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada (DAAC)](http://www.youradchoices.ca/)
  * French: Choix de Pub: [l’Alliance de la publicité numérique du Canada (DAAC)](http://www.youradchoices.ca/fr)

Additionally, in some versions of the Skype software that enable targeted ads, you may opt-out of Microsoft targeted ads displayed in the software by visiting the privacy options in the software or account settings menu. If you opt-out, you will still receive advertisements based on your country of residence, language preference, and IP address location, but other targeting information will not be used.

In some instances, Microsoft Advertising may facilitate the placement of advertisements in Skype software client by other online advertising networks. In some cases, these third parties may also place cookies on your computer and may collect information about your online activities across websites or online services. These companies currently include, but are not limited to: [24/7 Real Media](http://www.247realmedia.com/EN-US/), [aCerno,Inc](http://www.akamai.com/html/solutions/ads_predictive_segments.html), [AdBlade](http://www.adblade.com/), [AdConion](http://www.adconion.com/), [AdFusion](http://www.adfusion.com/), [Advertising.com](http://www.advertising.com/), [AppNexus](http://www.appnexus.com/), [Bane Media](http://www.banemedia.com/), [Brand.net](http://www.brand.net/), [CasaleMedia](http://www.casalemedia.com/), [Collective Media](http://www.collective.com/), [Interclick](http://www.interclick.com/), [Millennial](http://www.millennialmedia.com/), [ROI Media](http://roimediaconsultants.com/), [SpecificMedia](http://www.specificmedia.com/), [Tribal Fusion](http://www.tribalfusion.com/), [ValueClick](http://www.valueclickmedia.com/), [Yahoo!](http://advertising.yahoo.com/), [YuMe](http://www.yumenetworks.com/) and [Zumobi](http://www.zumobi.com/). If you have opted-out of targeted ads in the Skype client as outlined above, Skype will not pass any profile information to such advertising providers with the ad request. However, because these third parties may place cookies on your computer that facilitate their own targeting, the Skype opt-out mechanism described above will not necessarily prevent ad targeting by these companies. These companies may offer you a way to opt-out of ad targeting based on their cookies. You may find more information by clicking on the company names above and following the links to the Web sites of each company. Many of them are also members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) or the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA), which each provide a simple way to opt-out of ad targeting from participating companies.

## **6\. YOUR USER PROFILE**

Your user profile is the information provided by you at registration or later which is displayed in your Skype profile in the Skype software client, in the Skype search directory and on your personal details page in your account on [www.skype.com](http://www.skype.com/). It may include your Skype username, full name, address, telephone and mobile numbers, gender, date of birth, country, language, “about me” page URL, and any other information that you decide to make available. You can access your user profile from the “Skype” menu in the Skype software client or from your account on [www.skype.com](http://www.skype.com/) in order to view, correct or complete information, remove non-mandatory information; and to see the privacy settings associated with your profile information.

## **7\. LINKED WEBSITES AND THIRD PARTY APPLICATIONS**

Skype websites may contain links that will let you leave Skype's website and access another website. Linked websites are not under the control of Skype and these websites have different privacy policies. The Skype Privacy Policy applies solely to personal information that is acquired on the websites or through your use of the Skype software, Skype products and/or your relationship with Skype, so Skype urges you to be careful when you enter any personal information online. Skype accepts no responsibility or liability for these other websites.

If you use any extras, plug-ins or third party applications together with the Skype software or use any third party applications or products that incorporate or embed the Skype software (“Applications”), the provider of such Applications may obtain access to certain personal information about you. Skype does not and cannot control how the provider of Applications may use any personal information connected in connection with such Applications. Please ensure that you review any privacy policies or other terms applicable to the use of such Application before installation.

## **8\. HOW DOES SKYPE PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

Skype will take appropriate organizational and technical measures to protect the personal data and traffic data provided to it or collected by it with due observance of the applicable obligations and exceptions under the relevant legislation. Your personal and traffic data can only be accessed by authorized employees of Microsoft or its affiliates, subsidiaries or service providers who need to have access to this data in order to be able to fulfill their given duties.

Skype may use automated scanning within Instant Messages and SMS to (a) identify suspected spam and/or (b) identify URLs that have been previously flagged as spam, fraud, or phishing links; and (c) as part of our effort to protect the Skype software, products or our customers. In limited instances, Skype may capture and manually review instant messages or SMS in connection with these efforts. Skype may, in its sole discretion, block or prevent delivery of suspected Spam, and remove suspicious links or content from messages.

## **9\. PERSONAL DATA OF FRIENDS**

You may be interested in inviting your friends to join Skype. In the event you wish to use Skype's referral service, you will be directed to a webpage and will have the possibility of adding one or more email addresses in an online form. The information entered in this form, will only be used for the purposes of automatically generating an email message to these potential Skype users. By entering your friend’s email address you are confirming that your friend has consented to the supply of their details. Skype may identify you as the person who has made the referral in the invitation sent to your friend and will include your name, email address and/or phone number in such invitation.

## **10\. CONTACTING YOU**

Skype may from time to time ask you to provide information on your experiences which will be used to measure and improve quality. You are at no time under any obligation to provide any of such data. Any and all information which is voluntarily submitted in feedback forms on the website or any survey that you take part in is used for the purposes of reviewing this feedback and improving the Skype software, and Skype and other Microsoft products and websites.

Skype may contact you to send you messages about faults and service issues. Further, Skype reserves the right to use email, the Skype software or SMS to notify you of any eventual claims related to your use of Skype software, the Skype websites and/or Skype products, including without limitation claims of violation of third party rights.

Skype may send you alerts by email or SMS to notify you when someone has tried to contact you. Skype may also use email, SMS or the Skype software to keep you up to date with news about the Skype software and Skype products that you have purchased and/or to inform you about other Skype products or other Skype related information. You can opt-out of the receipt of alerts and/or promotional (a) emails by clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ link on the email that you receive or by changing your notification settings on your account page on [www.skype.com](http://www.skype.com/); and (b) SMS by following the instructions on the SMS that you receive.

If you have registered for or use co-branded Skype products, the emails or SMS that you receive may be from our partner company, acting on Skype’s behalf.

## **11\. HOW CAN YOU ACCESS OR AMEND YOUR PERSONAL DATA?**

You have the right to access and, where relevant, to amend your personal information. Some of your information may be viewed or edited online by signing into your account page on [www.skype.com](http://www.skype.com/). We will respond to requests to view, correct, complete or remove your personal information within a reasonable period of time and upon verification of your identity.

Skype will use all reasonable endeavours to accommodate requests to delete personal information unless it is required to be retained by law or for lawful business purposes. However, please note that due to the technical nature of the peer to peer network, it can sometimes take up to two weeks before your Skype ID disappears completely from the peer to peer network. Your details may still appear in the search directory during this time.

## **12\. HOW LONG IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA KEPT BY SKYPE?**

Skype will retain your information for as long as is necessary to: (1) fulfill any of the Purposes (as defined in article 2 of this Privacy Policy) or (2) comply with applicable legislation, regulatory requests and relevant orders from competent courts.

Retention of Instant Messages, Voice Messages, and Video Messages 

Your instant messages (IM), voicemail, and video messages, including any media that you share through our messaging features, such as videos, pictures, or your location on a map, (collectively “messages”) may be stored by Skype (a) to convey and synchronize your messages and (b) to enable you and your recipients to view the messages. Messages are generally stored by Skype between 30 or 90 days unless otherwise permitted or required by law. 

## **13\. MICROSOFT ACCOUNT**

Microsoft account (formerly known as Windows Live ID and Microsoft Passport) is a service that allows you to sign into Microsoft products (including Skype), web sites and services, as well as those of select Microsoft partners.

If you have a Skype account, you may connect it to a Microsoft account in order to view your contacts and other information from both accounts in one place. If you choose to connect your Skype account to your Microsoft account, Outlook.com users who communicate with you or who add you to their contacts may be invited to connect with you on Skype.

To use the Skype app on a Windows 8 or Windows 8.1 device, you must first sign into Windows with a Microsoft account. After you have launched the app for the first time, you will be signed into the app whenever you are signed into Windows with your Microsoft account on that same device. For more information about [Windows 8](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=190175) and [Windows 8.1](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=255232), please visit their privacy statements, located [here](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=280262) and [here](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?linkid=280270), respectively.

To view additional details about Microsoft account, including how to create and use a Microsoft account, how to edit account information, and how we collect and use information relating to a Microsoft account, please visit the Microsoft account [privacy statement](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=267635).

## **14\. CHILDREN**

Skype's websites and software clients are not intended for or designed to attract users under the age of 13. We encourage parents to be involved in the online activities of their children to ensure that no information is collected from a child without parental permission.

## **15\. MOBILE NOTIFICATIONS**

When you use Skype on your phone, Skype may use notification services available for that phone to let you know of incoming calls, chats and other messages when you are not actively running or using the Skype application. These services may be provided by a third party. For example, messages sent to an Apple device will use Apple’s Push Notification Services.

Notification services may receive information about the caller, sender of the message and the content of the message as part of providing the service and may use the information in accordance with the terms and conditions and privacy policy for the service provider. Skype is not responsible for the data collected by third party notification services.

If you do not want to use third party notification services to receive notification of incoming Skype calls and messages, you can disable this in **Settings >Notifications>Skype**.

## **16\. MAPPING AND LOCATION FEATURES**

If you agree to allow access to your location, Skype can use that information to provide services you request or to personalize your experience. For example, Skype may contain features that are based on the Bing Maps service or other third party map services that allow you to share your current location on a map or to search for items on a map, such as nearby Wi-Fi access points. When you request to plot your location on a map or to search for nearby Wi-Fi access points, your request is provided to Bing Maps and/or the third party map service for processing. Location information may include data available cell tower data, Wi-Fi hotspot data, and Global Position System (GPS) data.

When you use a Skype feature to plot your location using the Bing Maps service, Bing will collect those requests and Location-related information related to the requests may be used for calculating payments to Bing’s data vendors as part of operating the service. For more information on how Bing collects and uses information, go to <http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=248686>.

To learn more about how third party mapping services collect and use information, see the privacy statements for those services. Depending on the device you are using, Skype may use third party services to provide mapping services. For example, Skype may use Google maps on certain devices—you can learn more about the information that Google collects through its mapping services at <http://www.google.com/privacy.html>

When you use a location based service or feature, available cell tower data, Wi-Fi data and Global Position System (GPS) data may be sent to Microsoft. Microsoft uses location information to provide the services you request, personalize your experience and improve Microsoft products and services.

Certain services may allow you to control when location information is sent to Microsoft or made available to others. Refer to the documentation that came with your device for information about how to turn off location features.

## **17\. CAN THIS PRIVACY POLICY BE MODIFIED?**

Skype will occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our software and/or products and customer feedback. When we post changes to this Privacy Policy at [skype.com/go/privacy](http://www.skype.com/go/privacy), we will update the "last revised" date at the bottom of the Privacy Policy. If there are material changes to this Privacy Policy or in how we will use your personal information, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the change or by directly sending you a notification. You agree that your continued use of the Skype software or Skype products after notice shall constitute your acceptance of the Privacy Policy. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to be informed of how Skype is collecting, using, and protecting your information.

## **1 **8**. HOW CAN YOU CONTACT SKYPE?**

To contact Skype in relation to the “Skype” branded software or products, please submit a support request to [customer support team](http://support.skype.com/).   
Skype Software S.à r.l / Skype Communications S.à r.l.  
23-29 Rives de Clausen  
L-2165 Luxembourg  
Luxembourg

For members of Skype Manager in the United States only:  
Skype Inc.  
3210 Porter Drive  
Palo Alto, California 94304, USA

To find the Microsoft subsidiary in your country or region, see <http://www.microsoft.com/worldwide/>.

© Skype and/or Microsoft – Last updated: April 2014
